VINCENT J. SCHAEFER PAPERS (UA902.010) 1891-1993
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Environmentalism, 1940-1993; 8; 11.5
  - Subject Files, 1926-1992; Undated; 8.4
    - Citizens Guide to Adirondack Forest Preserve-publication, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 43)
    - The Cloud Splitter, 1944 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    - Commissioners Advisory Council on Museums, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 45)
    - Conservationists article and related materials, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 46)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1991 (Box 8, Folder 47)
    - Correspondence, Christmas Cards, photographs and news clippings, 1932-1936; Undated (Box 8, Folder 48)
    - Couch-SA-GA Association, 1977 (Box 8, Folder 49)
    - "The Months of Autumn," Albany, New York- Cryan, John F. and Dirig, Robert, 1977 December (Box 8, Folder 50)
    - Davitt Expedition Report, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 51)
    - Defeat the Recreational Amendment, correspondence, 1932 (Box 8, Folder 52)
    - Developing a Land Conservation Strategy-publication, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 53)
    - Drainage Basins of Streams Entering the Hudson River in Albany, Columbia, Greene, and Rensselaer Counties-report, 1963 (Box 8, Folder 54)
    - Eastern New York Solar Energy Society, Undated (Box 8, Folder 55)
    - Emergency Conservation Committee-Publication, 1929-1932 (Box 8, Folder 56)
    - Emerging Water Supply Technology Report, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 57)
    - Environmental Clearinghouse of Schenectady-ECOS News, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 58)
    - EOS, Transactions, American Geophysical Union- Newsletter, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 59)
    - Five Rivers Area, Maps, Undated (Box 8, Folder 60)
    - Five Rivers Environmental Center, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 61)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles" Insert of The Knickerbocker News including Wolf Hollow: Old Rock Scar, Noble Old Dutch Barns Are Dwindling & Air Pollution, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 62)
    - Five Rivers Rambles Topics (Box 8, Folder 63)
    - Flooding, Mohawk River, 1977-1978 (Box 8, Folder 64)
    - The Forest Preserve, 1948 (Box 8, Folder 65)
    - Friends of the Shawangunks, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 66)
    - Fulfilling the Promise of the Adirondack Park Volume 1, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 67)
    - The Geological History of the Mohawk Valley, Undated (Box 8, Folder 68)
    - The Fishes of the Adirondack Park, George, Carl J.-publications, 1980 August (Box 8, Folder 69)
    - Gore Mountain Ski Club, 1933-1934; Undated (Box 8, Folder 70)
    - Characteristics of New York Lakes Part 1-Gazetteer of Lakes, Ponds and Reservoirs, Greeson, Phillip E. and Robinson, F. Luman, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 71)
    - Characteristics of New York Lakes Part 1B-Gazetteer of Lakes, Ponds and Reservoirs by Drainage Basins Bulletin 68B, Greeson, Phillip E. and Williams, George E., 1970 (Box 8, Folder 72)
    - Ground Water Dependence in New York State-report, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 73)
    - Guide to the Catskills, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 74)
    - Guide to Trails of the West Central Adirondacks, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 75)
    - Gypsy Moth Aerial Spraying Project, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 76)
    - "A Moderate Approach", Hale, Edward and Barbara M.- The Lake Placid News, Undated (Box 8, Folder 77)
    - Ground Water in New York, Heath, Ralph C.- map, 1964 (Box 8, Folder 78)
    - Hidden Lake- notes and map, Undated (Box 8, Folder 79)
    - Hidden Lake- photograph, Undated (Box 8, Folder 80)
    - Historic Preservation in the Adirondack Park, Colloquium Proceeding, 1982 (Box 8, Folder 81)
    - Map of the Mountain Marcy Region, Hopkins, Arthurs, Conservation Department, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 82)
    - Horton Falls, 1926-1991; Undated (Box 8, Folder 83-84)
    - Horton Falls, 1926; 1987-1991; Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - The Hudson Valley Commission of New York Annual Report, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Lake George: A Mill Pond-publication, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letter to the Editor of Adirondack about VJ Schaefer, 1972 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Long Path- correspondence, clippings, photo, 1931-1932 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Long Path- correspondence, clippings, maps, 1988-1991 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Long Path- correspondence, news clippings & maps, 1974; 1985-1986; 1988 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Long Path- handwritten guide including menus, equipment & distances, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Long Path- handwritten notes and tree study notes, 1926; 1930; 1933 (Box 9, Folder 9-11)
    - Long Path- maps, routes and trail guides, 1924; 1932-1934; 1987; Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Long Path- Old Trail Camp, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Long Path- news clippings, 1934-1976 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Long Path- photographs, articles and correspondence, 1991-1992; Undated (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Long Path- trail notebook, 1928-1934; Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Maps- annotated and handwritten, 1936; Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Mohawk Islands Near Schenectady- manuscript and typescript, Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Mohawk River Drainage Basin- report, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club Administrative, 1930-1932; 1935 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- Appalachian Trail, 1933-1935; Undated (Box 9, Folder 22)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- birds, trees and plants, 1933; Undated (Box 9, Folder 23)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- correspondence, 1930; 1933-1936; 1938; 1977; Undated (Box 9, Folder 24)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- hiking schedules, 1929; Undated (Box 9, Folder 25)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- Long Path news clips, 1933-1934; Undated (Box 9, Folder 26)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- membership, 1930; 1933-1934; 1936; 1944; Undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- programs, bulletins and newsletters, 1934-1935; 1951; 1955; 1967; Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- news clips and photographs, 1932-1935; 1937; 1991; Undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- notes, including The Long Path, 1934-1935; Undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- snow train, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 31)
    - Mohawk Valley Hiking Club- songs, 1951; Undated (Box 9, Folder 32)
    - Mountain Magazine, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 33)
    - Mount Marcy Expedition, 1963 (Box 9, Folder 34)
    - National Speleological Society, 1960; 1962; 1964 (Box 9, Folder 35)
    - The Nature Conservancy, 1978; 1983; Undated (Box 9, Folder 36)
    - The Nature Conservancy- memorandums, Project Acquisition Proposals & Book of trustee Meeting Minutes, 1970; 1972-1975; 1983 (Box 9, Folder 37)
    - Niagara Mohawk Power Corporation, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 38)
    - New York Environmental News, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 39)
    - The New York State Council of Environmental Advisers, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - New York State Rare Plant Status List, 1992 (Box 9, Folder 41)
    - Normanskill- News clippings and correspondence, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 42)
    - Notes on environmental topics, 1934; Undated (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Notes on the Second Adirondack Conference, Undated (Box 9, Folder 44)
    - NY-NJ Trail Conference- Holiday Catalog, 1985 (Box 9, Folder 45)
    - Old Corner Tree- map, Undated (Box 9, Folder 46)
    - Old Maids Woods Committee of the Nature Conservancy- meeting minutes, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 47)
    - Old Maids Woods Committee of the Nature Conservancy, 1972-1973; 1980; Undated (Box 9, Folder 48)
    - Periods of Records of Selected Streams, 1924-1950 (Box 9, Folder 49)
    - "Watchdog of the Forest Preserve", Oilcher, Edith-Conservationist, 1984 January-1984 February (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Pine Bush Unique Area Unit Management plan, 1986; 1991 (Box 9, Folder 51)
    - Pitch Pine, 1989 (Box 9, Folder 52)
    - A Preliminary Guide to New York State Trees, Undated (Box 9, Folder 53)
    - Santanon, Preserve- map, Undated (Box 9, Folder 54)
    - Save the Redwoods League, Undated (Box 9, Folder 55)
    - Schaefer Notes on the Schenectady Area, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Defending the Wilderness," Schaefer, Paul, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "The Adirondack- The Making of a Relief Man", Schaefer, Paul, 1956 March 01 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "The Making of a Wilderness," Schaefer, Paul, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Recollections of Incident with Frank C. Moore," Schaefer, Paul, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Adventuring Down the Long Brown Park," Schaefer, Vincent, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "The Adirondacks: A Unique Resource," paper delivered at Union College, Schaefer, Vincent, 1980 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - "The Beauty that Falls from the Sky," Schaefer, Vincent, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: An Adventure in the Kaiparowits Country", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1972 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Big Nose: 'Snake Country' ", Schaefer, Vincent J.- The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 21-Mar-72 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Englands Woods: Spring Hideaway," Schaefer,Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 March 22 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Gore, a Most Remarkable Mountain," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles #13: Gore- A Skier's Delight," Schaefer, Vincent J.- Typescript, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Helderbergs: Ice Land," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 January 05 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Helderbergs: A Unique Heritage," Schaefer,Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Little Nose," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Past, Present, and Future of the Pine Plains," Schaefer,Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1971 July 22 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Satellite Peaks Hills Surround Gore Mountain," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Schoharie Valley: A Trail of Memories," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1971 November 02 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: Some Fascinating Features of the Glenville Hills," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Touareuna: Where we Dwell Together," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Valley of the Schoharie," Schaefer,Vincent J.- The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: What Have We Done to This Beautiful Land?" (Typescript), 1971 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - "Five Rivers Rambles: The Yantaputchaberg," Schaefer, Vincent J.-The Knickerbocker News-Union Star, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - "The Founding of the Long Path," Schaefer, Vincent J.- Trail Walker, 1986 February-1986 March (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - "Long Path of New York", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1935 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - "A Matter of Policy", Schaefer, Vincent J.- typescript, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - "Memorandum Relative to The Long Path of New York", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1974 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - "The Old Maid's Woods- A Remnant of The Pine Plains", Schaefer, Vincent J., 1967; 1971-1973 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - "Purple Mountains Majesty", Schaefer, Vincent J.- photocopied manuscript, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Schenectady Bird Club- brochure, 1947-1948 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Schenectady County Aquifer Preservation Study and Report, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Schenectady County Chamber of Commerce, Environmental Advisory Council, 1978-1979 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Schenectady County Conservation Council- report, 1932 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Schenectady County Planning Departmental Newsletter- "Planning", 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Schenectady Cycling Club, Constitution, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Schenectady Riverside Flood Research Committee, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Schenectady Winter Sports Club, 1931; 1935-1936; 1962; Undated (Box 11, Folder 6-7)
    - Snow Train Bulletin, 1935 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Society for Preservation of Water Resources, Inc., 1982-1985 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - State of New York Conservation Department- map, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area- Maps and History, 1936 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Survey of History and Natural Sciences of the Five Rivers Area, Undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Torreya- With photograph of Schaefer and his Notes, 1933-1934 (Box 11, Folder 14)
    - Town of Rotterdam Correspondence, 1971 (Box 11, Folder 15)
    - Trail Walker- Newspaper, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Trancik, Roger- Hamlets of the Adirondacks, Ithaca, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 17)
    - Tree Study, Undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - "Unit Planning for Wilderness Management," VanValkenburgh, Norman J.- The Association for the Protection of the Adirondacks Special Report, 1987 Spring (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Vroman's Nose Preservation Corporation- Financial Report, Annual Meeting Minutes & Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1987-1990 (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Vroman's Nose- Maps, reprinted maps, correspondence, 1978; 1984; Undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Vroman's Nose Preservation Corporation-Newsletter, 1985-1987 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Vroman's Nose- Reprinted articles,maps, correspondence & photos, 1941-1943; 1984; Undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Vroman's Nose- Reprints, maps & correspondence, 1933; 1947; 1984; Undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Waterman, Laura and Guy- "Forest and Crag", 1986 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - An Environmental Survey of the Mohawk River Valley-Waterways '73 Volume 1, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - An Environmental Survey of the Mohwawk River Valley-Waterways '73 Volume 2, 1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - "Whiteface Mountain and Its Easier Ice," Manuscript Fragment, Undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Whiteface Mountain Ski Report, Undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - WINN-E-COMAC Club, 1935; 1939; 1942; 1948 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Photographs, 1922-1986; Undated; 8.5
    The photographs in this subseries date from Schaefer's teenage years all the way through his retirement after he left the Atmospheric Sciences Research Center. Having a love and deep respect for the outdoors from a young age, Schaefer participated in organized activities like the Mohawk Valley Hiking Club, but he also incorporated spontaneous outdoor adventures into his busy schedule whenever he could. Sometimes this meant a day or afternoon exploring areas in and around the Capital Region; other times it meant taking time to explore while he was away on business. His work for General Electric, Munitalp, and the State University at Albany/ASRC (not to mention his extensive consulting) offered ample opportunities to venture into mountain ranges, deserts, plains, valleys, and forests to pursue environmental studies that were of interest to him.
    This subseries includes many photo negatives and slides in addition to traditional photographs and are identified as such in their folder titles.
    - Adirondack Trail Club- photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Adirondacks-slides, Undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Augur Falls, Sacandaga River-photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Australia- slides, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Bacteria- photographs, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Bellata Ranch- negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Big Prairie- negatives, 1953 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Birds- photographs, Undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Bonito Lava Flow- negatives, 1963 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Bridges- photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - California- negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Canandaigua Lake- slides, Undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Canoeing, 1931 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Canyon Land- negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Cedar Ranch Petrified Wood- slides, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Clouds and Cloud Formations-slides, 1957-1978 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Colorado River Trips-slides, 1969-1973 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Columbia Gorge-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Crater Lake-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Crater, SP-slides, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Crystals, Gypsum-photo, Undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
    - Dams-photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Devils Post Pile California-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Devils Tower-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Dewdrops-photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
    - Dunes, Sand-photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Dust Cloud Mount Saint Helen's-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - East-slides, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - East Pocket Ridge-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Edith Park Slash from Clear Cut-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Environmental-slides, 1971 (Box 13, Folder 31)
    - Farming-photographs, Undated (Box 13, Folder 32)
    - Fiji Island-slides, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 33)
    - Five Rivers Rambles-articles, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Five Rivers Rambles-negatives, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Fog Woestyne-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - Fungus-photo, Undated (Box 13, Folder 37)
    - Geology-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 38)
    - Giant Mountain-negatives, 1964-1965 (Box 13, Folder 39)
    - Glacier Park-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 40)
    - Grand Falls-negatives, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 41)
    - Great Sand Dunes, Colorado-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 42)
    - Great Smokies East-slides, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 43)
    - Grand Tetons-negatives, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 44)
    - Great Flats Aquifer-negatives, 1938 (Box 13, Folder 45)
    - Great Flats Aquifer-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 46)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13, Folder 47)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13, Folder 48)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, 1958-1963 (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - Helderbergs-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 50)
    - Hidden Lakes-photos, Undated (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Hiking-negatives, 1952 (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - Hiking-negatives, Undated (Box 13, Folder 53)
    - Hiking-photographs, Undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Hiking-photographs, Undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Huyck Preserve-photos, Undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Ice- slides, 1956-1986 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Ice- slides, 1962-1973 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Ice Cone and Pillar Minelot Falls, Helderbergs, New York-photo, Undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Ice Stalagmites-photograph, Undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Ice Stalagmites, Tory Cave, Helderberg Mountains-photograph, Undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Ice Storms-negatives, 1964-1972 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Indian Ladder Cliffs-photographs, 1931 January (Box 14, Folder 10)
    - Insects-photographs, 1943 (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Japan-slides, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 12)
    - Kings Highway Schenectady, Albany- negatives, Undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
    - Kings Road Pine Bush-negatives, Undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Kings Road Vyt Kyck-negatives, Undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Kunjamuch Cave, Adirondacks-photos, Undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1952-1973 (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1953-1967 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1954-1976 (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1970 (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1976 (Box 14, Folder 21-22)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1955-1981 (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1956-1967 (Box 14, Folder 24)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1956-1978 (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1972 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1974 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1957-1977 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1958-1967 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1958-1978 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1959-1972 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1966 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1968 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1969 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1970 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962; 1966; Undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1972 (Box 16, Folder 1-5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1973 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1974 (Box 16, Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1975 (Box 16, Folder 9-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1976 (Box 17, Folder 1-7)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1977 (Box 17, Folder 8-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1978 (Box 17, Folder 10-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1979 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1960-1984 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1965 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1971 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1972 (Box 18, Folder 6-7)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1974 (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1976 (Box 18, Folder 9-12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1976 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1978 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1961-1981 (Box 19, Folder 3-4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1972 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1974 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1976 (Box 19, Folder 7-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1962-1977 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1972 (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1973 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1974 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1975 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1978 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1963-1979 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1972 (Box 20, Folder 7-9)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1974 (Box 20, Folder 10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1975 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1976 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1964-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1965-1976 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1965-1984 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1968 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1972 (Box 21, Folder 5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1974 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1975 (Box 21, Folder 7-8)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1977 (Box 21, Folder 9-10)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1966-1978 (Box 21, Folder 11)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1971 (Box 21, Folder 12)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1975 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1968-1977 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1972-1976 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1972-1977 (Box 22, Folder 4-5)
    - Land Formations-slides, 1975-1978 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Lewis Lake-negatives, 1953 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Little Lake Cran, MI-slides, Undated (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Louisiana-slides, 1971-1972 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Mann Gulah Fire Tragedy-photograph of site, 1949 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Maroon Bells, Colorado-negatives, 1966 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Mesa Verde National Park Colorado, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Metcalf Lake-negatives, Undated (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Michigan-negatives, 1928 (Box 22, Folder 14)